Marshall Asch

hello@marshallasch.ca marshallasch.ca in/MarshallAsch

У @MarshallAsch

@MarshallAsch



I am a Master of Computer Science with a love for wireless mesh networks and DevOps. Over the past several years I have been working on a project to help close the digital divide in Northern Canada. I have also been falling in love with the realm of DevOps through my constant desire to achieve better pipelines to validate my code as well as to publish and deploy new versions in all of my various side projects, masters research, and personal server deployments. In my past work experience I have been converting all the manually configured infrastructure to use Terraform IaC to de-silo the knowledge and to demystify the services that we depend on.

I have a passion for command-line tools, networking, servers, and open source projects. Most of my work has been on cli tools, DevOps tasks, and backend systems.

Education

M.Sc. Computer Science, University of Guelph, Canada in Mesh Networking. 2019 - 2022

B.Comp. (Hons) Computer Science, University of Guelph, Canada. 2015 - 2019 Degree with Distinction Recognition for Outstanding Academic Performance.

Open Source Projects

OO Resources O Offline Open source teaching resource to provide interactive 10/2021 - Present course content and development dependencies in one place that does not require internet access.

05/2021 - Present **ns-3 Github CI pipeline** Continuous development tool to verify that modules built of the ns-3 network simulator compile and run as intended.

2021 - Present ns-3 Static Access Frequency Module () Implemented and maintaining a module for the ns-3 network simulator.

> ns-3 RHPMAN Module Implemented and maintaining a module for the ns-3 network simulator.

liquidctl maintainer • Active Maintainer on the python liquid cooler controller 2020 - Present CLI application

Botomir maintainer Active Maintainer on the node S Discord Bot application 2021 - Present

Certification and Training

Moo1 - MongoDB Basics Course. MonogoDB University. 2021

M103 - MongoDB Basic Cluster Administration Course. MonogoDB University.

M121 - MongoDB Aggregation Framework Course. MonogoDB University.

Employment History

01/2021 - Present **DevOps Engineer**, Value Connect, Guelph, ON.

01/2021 - 06/2021 **Graduate Teaching Assistant (Compilers)**, University of Guelph, ON.

09/2020 - 12/2020**Graduate Teaching Assistant (Cloud Computing)**, University of Guelph, ON.

01/2020 - 04/2020 Graduate Teaching Assistant (Operating Systems), University of Guelph, ON.

09/2019 - 08/2020 **Left Mitacs Accelerate Intern**, University of Guelph, ON.

09/2019 - 12/2019 Graduate Teaching Assistant (Microcomputers), University of Guelph, ON.

Employment History (continued)

05/2019 - 08/2019 University of Guelph Mitacs Accelerate Intern, Left, Maple Ridge, BC.

01/2019 - 04/2019 Lead Developer and Undergraduate Research Assistant, Working on the eNuk project, University of Guelph, ON.

> Undergraduate Teaching Assistant (Introduction to Computer Applications), University of Guelph, ON.

05/2018 - 08/2018 **Mobile App Developer**, Left, Maple Ridge, BC.

05/2017 - 08/2017 **IT Student**, Lakeridge Health, Oshawa, ON.

06/2016 - 08/2016 High Ropes Instructor, Camp New Moon, ON

06/2015 - 08/2015 High Ropes Instructor, Camp New Moon, ON

06/2014 - 08/2014 **High Ropes Instructor**, Camp New Moon, ON

Volunteer and Extra-Curricular Experience

Volunteering

01/2021 - Present **Road2IR**, Provided technical and networking infrastructure advice.

10/2019 Ontario University Fair, Represented the University of Guelph, Toronto, ON.

09/2019 - 04/2020 **Guelph Coding Community**, Student club executive, Guelph, ON.

09/2019 - 12/2019 Climbing Gym Monitor, University of Guelph, ON.

> 12/2019 Major League Hacking, Local Hack Day event Organizer, Society of Computing and Information Science, Guelph, ON.

12/2018 Major League Hacking, Local Hack Day event Organizer, Society of Computing and Information Science, Guelph, ON.

Society of Computing and Information Science, System Administrator, Uni-

versity of Guelph, ON.

04/2017 - 06/2018 Full Stack Developer, ActivNtel, Guelph, ON.

01/2016 - 02/2017 Climbing Gym Monitor, University of Guelph, ON.

09/2016 - 06/2017 **Web Developer**, NGTronix, Guelph, ON.

Committees

09/2018 - 04/2020

09/2019 - 03/2022IT Strategy Advisory Committee. University of Guelph, ON.

01/2018 - 04/2019 Roboticon Planning Committee Society of Computing and Information Science,

Guelph, ON.

09/2017 - 04/2019 Computer Infrastructure Committee School of Computer Science, University

of Guelph, ON.

Curriculum Committee School of Computer Science, University of Guelph, ON. 09/2018 - 04/2019

Awards and Recognitions

03/2022 eCampus Virtual Learning Strategy Grant, (\$50,000) Research grant to develop open source, open teaching resources.

09/2020 University of Guelph GSA Conference Runner up, Awarded to the two runner-up presenters for the student run conference.

Erin Angus Graduate Student Award. Awarded to a graduate student for making signifi-04/2020 cant contributions to student life by Graduate Student Association.

Awards and Recognitions (continued)

- **CEPS Dean's Tri-Council Scholarship**, (\$5,000) Deans Scholarship awarded to NSERC award holders, University of Guelph, ON.
- Canada Graduate Scholarships-Master's Program, (\$17,500) Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC) Scholarship, University of Guelph, ON.
- O2/2020 Ontario Graduate Scholarship, (\$5,000) A merit based academic scholarship, University of Guelph, ON.
- o5/2019 College of Engineering and Physical Sciences Society of Excellence, Demonstrated academic excellence and outstanding contributions to the university community, University of Guelph, ON.
 - College of Engineering and Physical Science Deans Honours List, University of Guelph, ON. F15, W16, F16, W17, F17, W18, F18, W19
- Dr. James Linders Scholarship. (\$500) Awarded for achieving the highest third year average by the School of Computer Science, University of Guelph, ON.
- 09/2015 University of Guelph Entrance Scholarship. (\$2,000) Awarded for being admitted with an average greater than 85% by the University of Guelph, ON.

Research Grants

- 04/2020 Northern Scientific Training Program. (\$2,150) Awarded to conduct fieldwork in Northern Canada by Polar Knowledge Canada.
- 04/2019 Northern Scientific Training Program. (\$2,307) Awarded to conduct fieldwork in Northern Canada by Polar Knowledge Canada.

Non Academic Presentations

- 09/2020 Introduction to Git, Guelph Coding Community, Guelph, ON.
- o3/2020 MSc. Seminar Incorporation of Human Mobility in Data Replication Schemes in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks, Guelph Coding Community, Guelph, ON.
- o9/2019 Advanced Git, Guelph Coding Community, Guelph, ON.
 - Introduction to BASH and Git, Guelph Coding Community, Guelph, ON.
- 12/2018 Major League Hacking Localhost Workshop, Society of Computing and Information Science, Guelph, ON.
- 11/2018 **Mesh Networking**, Guelph Coding Community, Guelph, ON.

Research Publications

Conference Proceedings

- **Asch**, **M.**, Versluis, A., Gillis, D., & McCuaig, J. (2022). A Self Contained, Interactive Open Educational Resource for Object Oriented Programming. In *Inted* 2022 proceedings. in press.

- Asch, M., Seymour, P. F., Ernst, J., & Gillis, D. (2019). Incorporation of Node Mobility in Data Replication Schemes in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks. In 2019 IEEE 10th Annual Information Technology, Electronics and Mobile Communication Conference (IEMCON) (pp. 0230–0236). Oral presentation and Preceding. 6 doi:10.1109/IEMCON.2019.8936268
- Durish, N., Gillis, D., Seymour, P. F., Rourke, K., **Asch**, **M.**, Raturi, S., ... Ernst, J. (2019). Bridging the Digital Divide in the Circumpolar North [abstract]. In *Labrador research forum*, Happy Valley-Goose Bay, Labrador, Canada.
- Gillis, D., Durish, N., Rourke, K., **Asch**, **M.**, Knarr, J., Samuels, J., ... Harper, S. L. (2019). Supporting Community-Based Monitoring with Technology in the Circumpolar North [abstract]. In *Labrador research forum*, Happy Valley-Goose Bay, Labrador, Canada.
- Durish, N., Gillis, D., Seymour, P. F., Rourke, K., **Asch**, **M.**, Raturi, S., ... Ernst, J. (2018). Bridging the Digital Divide to Support Community-Based Monitoring in the Circumpolar North [abstract]. In *Arcticnet*, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.

Conference Presentations

- **Asch**, **M.**, Lin, X., & Gillis, D. (2020). Impact of Social Interactions on Mobile Ad Hoc Networks. Graduate Students Association Virtual Conference, Guelph, Canada.
- Asch, M., Rourke, K., Seymour, P. F., Durish, N., Flowers, C., Wood, M., ... Ernst, J. (2019). Bridging the Digital Divide with Mobile Ad Hoc Networks in the Circumpolar North. Western Student Research Conference, London, Canada.

Skills

Languages Java, sql, BASH, Languages Java, sql, BASH, Languages Java, sql, BASH, Languages

Databases Mysql, MongoDB.

Frameworks Express[S, Discord[S, ns-3, Nginx Web Server, Spring Boot

Tools git, GitHub Actions, Bitbucket Pipelines, aws, Ansible, Terraform, Docker, Docker-Compose.

References

Available on Request

Last updated: April 7, 2022